SHAYNE F. PRESTON

PROFILE

Self-motivated and highly skilled Senior Software Engineer with over 5 years of experience in web development. Recognized for a positive and ambitious attitude, as well as above and beyond day-to-day work ethic and efficiency. Clear communicator with great leadership skills seeking challenging opportunities at the intersection of business solutions and cutting edge web applications.

EXPERIENCE

DraftkingsSenior Software Engineer

Boston, Massachusetts April 2022 - Present

- Technical lead for Draftkings' microfrontend Quick Deposit application, ensuring trust and convenience when depositing money onto the platform by keeping users within their product.
- Worked with 3rd party vendors like Apple Pay, and led implementations of new deposit options that saw over \$100 million of deposits in four months.
- Setup up internal code test coverage analysis, threat detection, monitoring, and logging to alert developers early of bugs before they reach production.

FactSet Research Systems

Software Engineer III

Boston, Massachusetts July 2019 - April 2022

- Created and maintained core applications for FactSet's Research Business Unit.
 These apps provided real-time news, events, and signals to both Buy Side and Sell Side clients. They are a cornerstone to the FactSet Software Suite, receiving over ten thousand requests per product per day.
- Managed and agile team to create stable and shareable UI components and APIs to improve standardization and usage of news and calendar events for clients.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Quick Deposit

Draftkings, 2023

- Utilized Remix and Kubernetes to create a diagonally scaleable server side rendered microfrontend.
- Worked with multiple departments to ensure easy integration with current and future products.

WebSocket Spotify Game

Personal Project, 2023

- Multiplayer web game that utilizes Node.js and WebSockets to create curated music trivia questions based on users' Spotify data.
- The underlying game infrastructure is fully scalable due to utilizing Redis' PubSub model to listen to changes in the state of a trivia room.

SKILLS

Javascript/Typescript, Git, Remix, React, Vue, Golang, Node.js, Express, Test Driven Development, AWS, CI/CD, SQL, RESTful API

EDUCATION

Bachelors in Computer and Systems Engineering

Troy, New York August 2015 - May 2019

Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute